<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Jinxi Xiang</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu5b01fa446aee0ba96e6466015afa9712_7278_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Will Transform The Way We Learn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ai_edu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ai_edu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a multidisciplinary researcher, I have worked on many different projects in universities and industry. Like many other engineering students who major in &amp;rsquo;traditional engineering,&amp;rsquo; which has been developing for decades, I witnessed the decline of these subjects, which are overtaken by AI overnight. For example, as an undergraduate student, I struggled to learn the basic theory of signal processing, which is overwhelmed by a mathematical wall. As a reviewer for signal processing-related papers in recent years, I saw no related up-to-date research based on the traditional methodology. Instead, AI models with large-scale data collection and developing well-designed training paradigms surpass the conventional methods by a large margin. That makes me wonder where our way of learning is heading in the era of AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-impact-of-ai-on-higher-education&#34;&gt;The Impact of AI on Higher Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence will take over human capability (not intelligence) in the near future. The fundamental reason is that machines can keep learning infinitely while our biological limitations bind humans. We need rest, leisure, and entertainment, and we have sinful laziness occasionally. All these limitations are not present in machines. The impact of artificial intelligence on higher education is as significant as the birth of modern universities in Europe in the twelfth century, marking a fundamental transformation. AI will rebuild all subjects. In the future, as artificial intelligence develops rapidly, the existing university organizational structures, disciplinary systems, knowledge frameworks, and teaching methods could be completely dismantled and rebuilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of artificial intelligence on higher education is as significant as the birth of modern universities in Europe in the twelfth century, marking a fundamental transformation. All subjects will be rebuild by AI. In the future, as artificial intelligence develops rapidly, the existing university organizational structures, disciplinary systems, knowledge frameworks, and teaching methods could be completely dismantled and rebuilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-core-of-education&#34;&gt;The Core of Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we train students, we must cultivate great wisdom and let them have some small cleverness. The great wisdom here refers to grasping the principal contradictions, grasping the essence of things, and understanding the basic operating principles. For example, I know the principles of architecture and design, and at the same time, I can master the technical details of things through practice. Mastering great wisdom requires combining theory and practice. People must think and act deeply enough on specific issues before appreciating the great wisdom involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-scientific-research&#34;&gt;The Future Scientific Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have always believed that scientific research must be based on understanding. You must thoroughly understand the theory behind the matter so that what you want to do can be realized. For tomography imaging, for example, we traditionally need to model the forward function through electromagnetic principles with multiphysics simulations. Later, we found that end-to-end learning with a network without such knowledge works quite well. Artificial intelligence does not follow common sense at all. Its value is precisely reflected in its &amp;ldquo;unexplainability&amp;rdquo;. Simply put, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand how things work but can get things done. This feeling is like a bird that can fly but doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how. In retrospect, this &amp;ldquo;inexplicability&amp;rdquo; seems incredible but also more natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, the scientific research paradigm will be completely different from the past and the future: How should people do scientific research based on understanding? Or use enough data to train artificial intelligence and use it for scientific research? It can be said that scientific research has entered a new era utterly different from the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I would say in medical AI; clinical professionals still require explanations for AI reasoning. Having our paper published is an indispensable part of the process. However, in the future, as the growth of AI and more validations are shown in practical scenarios, we will get used to the new paradigm with explainable reasoning and trust the outputs of AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ackonelwdgeent: &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.eol.cn/xueshu/hui/202404/t20240410_2597821.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Xing Li (Tsinghua University)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia GTC 2024!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/gtc_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/gtc_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;png&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/gtc_2024/IMG_7612_hu072ff66da824571d5d3f0886c8a27def_15886091_95ea2e85cb1ee718079d33212408f628.webp 400w,
               /post/gtc_2024/IMG_7612_hu072ff66da824571d5d3f0886c8a27def_15886091_022979eae79c2745c00255b5c0dc172b.webp 760w,
               /post/gtc_2024/IMG_7612_hu072ff66da824571d5d3f0886c8a27def_15886091_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/post/gtc_2024/IMG_7612_hu072ff66da824571d5d3f0886c8a27def_15886091_95ea2e85cb1ee718079d33212408f628.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;570&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
